start with an equilateral triangle and
cut it into nine congruent equilateral
triangles and shade four of them thus
shading 49ths of the area of the
equilateral triangle now repeat this
process on the top four nths cutting it
into nine pieces and shading four of
them so that we've shaded four nths of
four kns of the area we can repeat this
process over and over again each time
taking the unshaded top four kns from
before cutting it into nine pieces and
shading four of them if we imagine
carrying this process out infinitely
often then we get a diagram that
represents the infinite sum the infinite
sum is a limit so in this limiting
diagram we've shaded the infinite sum of
the powers of 49ths on the other hand if
we look at each level along the way we
see that in each level we've shaded four
of five congruent triangles therefore
the infinite sum of the powers of 49ths
must equal 4 fths